Welcome to 2024 BBRE Awards, where
I will show you the best bug bounty
blog posts and write ups of 2024.
I have prepared four categories,
the best blog post, the best tool,
the best underrated and the best
overall bug bounty write up of 2024.
And I want to mention here that I am not
competing with the Port Swigger list.
I think that list is great.
It's just, they focus more on the
research aspect while I focus strictly
on bug bounty and, uh, things that
are relevant, things that are write
ups from real bug bounty targets.
And, uh, I hope you,
you will enjoy the list.
And With that out of the way,
let's jump to the first category,
which is the best blog post and it
was very difficult to choose one.
So I also have two honorable mentions
and we start with the first one.
It is the blog post by Doomer
Hunter called 200k in two weeks.
A clickbait title, but
hopefully valuable advice.
It is a very valuable advice about
participating in the life hacking events.
Uh, do more hunter also described
what a life hacking event is.
If you're not familiar of why people
like me are so hyped about the LAGs,
this is the good blog post to, to
get started and then to also learn.
their approach because it's, it's
written by Doomer Hunter, but they
were collaborating with gather chat and
yeah, they had an incredible result.
They described all their methodology,
their approach, what worked, what didn't.
And, uh, I really, really like this one.
If you like this blog post, also check
out our interview with Doomer Hunter.
He was here in this studio actually a few
weeks ago and, uh, we had some fun and
we recorded a very, very good episode.
So make sure to check this out.
Then another honorable mention
here goes to Shreyas Chavhan.
I hope I read it more or less correctly.
If I'm not, I am very sorry.
Um, he describes his whole
journey and this blog post
is about his first 12 months.
And the detail that he
describes is incredible.
You can see the charts, you can see
the time spent, you can see everything.
I think I was the one that started
doing something like this, but I think
he takes it even further and I, I just
love to see, see things like that.
I think it's very easy to.
Share your earnings and things like that.
Once you're already established, once
you're making hundreds of thousands of
dollars a year, but what is really hard
and really valuable as well is doing
it from the very beginning and This is
exactly what happens on this blog post.
It is incredible and Yeah.
Uh, I wish Shreyas, uh, a lot of good
luck and, um, and I hope he will continue
describing his, his journey like this,
but then the award can only be one.
And in my opinion, the best
bug bounty blog post of 2024
was this one by Douglas Day.
How I became the most valuable hacker.
It's about Douglas experience
at age one, three Oh five.
where, uh, he won the NVH belt,
which is a huge, huge achievement.
It is my dream to, to
get this belt one day.
So I really, really, um, I'm going to
come back to this blog posts, uh, over
and over again, specifically, I would say
this paragraph that finding bugs is easy
and the hard part is finding the scope.
It's kind of captures.
Everything that I've learned last year
while hanging out with the best bug bounty
hunters in the world It's something that
I've noticed that at this level, once
you're at the LAG level More or less
everyone has the same advanced knowledge
of all vulnerability classes Of course,
everyone or most people have one bug
class where they are exceptional And
let's say they are exceptional at XSS
They can find XSS where other hunters
would just give up at some point.
But most of the bugs, they do not
require this level of knowledge.
And the hard part is finding the
scope, is being in the correct place,
is finding the correct application,
access to this application.
And this is basically what, what
Douglas described in in this blog post
and in this paragraph specifically.
So I would say this is the most valuable
bug bounty advice that personally I
learned throughout the whole last year.
So the first BBRE award
ever goes to Douglas.
I think for the next year, if I continue
doing this, I will actually Get some
physical rewards and I'll ship them to
the winners But we'll see we'll see how
it goes If you would like to see that let
me know in the comment and I will make
sure to plan it That way the next year
With top blog posts out of the way, we'll
go to the next category Which is top tool
and also I have two honorable mentions
here The first one is Lemma by Devparam.
You can see this is my GitHub
account, but it is not because
I want to take credit for it.
It's because this tool was so good that
Devparam was asked to take it down.
Well, actually, he was asked to take it
down because of breach of some rules, but
let's say it was too good to be working.
What it does is it gives you a terminal.
And in a very, very seamless way,
distribute your workload across
thousands of instances of, um, of
lambdas, I think, which basically
allows you to bypass right limiting.
And I saw this being very, very
useful in in real attacks, real
attacks in real bug bounty reports.
So it is very, very, very good tool.
If you will.
Do an attack that requires you
to bypass the rate limiting
through by locking the IP address.
This is the tool that you want to use.
Another honorable mention goes to the
CSP bypass search website by Renipak.
He aggregated a lot of
publicly known CSP bypasses.
So if you have an XSS But it's
blocked by CSP and either you're
not skilled enough to find a
bypass yourself or you're too lazy.
This is the website, um,
which you should open.
You should look for known bypasses.
Um, I think it is, it is very,
very useful because I'm definitely
too lazy to find bypasses myself.
So I appreciate it.
A lot.
But again, the award is only one.
And in my opinion, the best tool of 2024
was HTTP garden by nerve industries.
It is the tool that allows you to find
inconsistencies between HTTP parsers.
So you will have a reverse proxy
in the middle and then the server
in the back end and you can send
specific payloads and hoping that
one of the two will https: otter.
ai It works if you want to find
a bug like request smuggling or
something similar like that I think
this tool it is really advanced.
It does really advanced analysis to
to make these attacks possible There
is also a whole talk about these
attacks, which is really really good.
There are also A lot of examples
in this repo about attacks.
You can try or some inconsistencies
that happen that maybe some of them
are fixed, but some of them are still
in the wild because they weren't
exploited in a real world target.
So nobody wanted to fix them, but maybe
in a very specific situation you will.
I can definitely attribute one of
my findings directly to this tool,
to this repository, I'm sorry.
So, um, I think it is the best
tool of 2024 and the best tool
award goes to ACDP garden.
With that said, uh, we have two out of
four categories out of the way, and now
we'll go to the top underrated category.
And I also have two honorable mentions
here and one very, very clear winner.
Each of these blog posts, I would say
is underrated for different reasons.
The first one is the zoom session
takeover by basically exploiting an XSS
in the, in the cookie and this blog post.
It is really, really, really well
written, you know, the previous
category top blog post, it was
about blog posts and not write ups.
So I didn't consider write
ups for that category.
In terms of the quality of the write
up, I would say this is the best
blog post that I am covering today.
And the way it is
explained is really clear.
Um, it's sort of an XSS with the
way how to basically how to find
the gadget to exploit the it.
XSS in a cookie, uh, covers a lot of
basics, but then it goes to the part
where to show the account takeover or
the session takeover, to be very precise.
It also describes the oath.
If you're a member of VBR premium and
you've read the oath articles, this is
not going to be something too new to you.
You should be familiar with the
techniques used here, but if
you're not, if you're not a member,
check out this blog post because.
It describes really well how you
use XSS to steal the, the access
token by abusing the outflow.
So, uh, like what, what is the state?
Why the state has to be set?
What is the selected account parameter?
All of these things are really,
really well explained here.
So this blog post is, is really nice.
The reason why it landed in the
Underrated category is that it was
rated by zoom as a medium because they
differentiate between account takeover,
which is a persistent account takeover
and session takeover, which means you
can just take over the user session.
And the researchers also started
to, to like show more impact in the
way of, um, for example, capturing
the video of the, of the victim,
because it's a zoom and zoom website.
If you're using zoom, uh, to have a
conference call through the browser, the
browser will have the permission to, to
use your camera, to use your microphone.
I think everyone is aware that the
JavaScript that's executed as the
result of an XSS also has access
to your camera, to your microphone,
but it's something that I think it
won't upgrade your severity directly
from medium to high because it's
not actually something unexpected.
But if the program is maybe 50 50
between rating your back as a medium
and as a high and you do something
like this, you will get the higher
severity or maybe you will get the lower
severity, but you will get a bonus.
Just I think putting something like
this in your report is very nice and I
actually don't know if this was Eventually
upgraded from medium to high because
the blog post doesn't doesn't say it.
I think it means it wasn't upgraded It
stayed as a medium because they I think
they would write it otherwise but I
think it's a really, really nice attack.
Good chain.
Very, very good blog post.
So if it stayed as a medium, I think
it is, uh, underrated, not because I
think zoom has mishandled it in a way.
I just think a lot of
work was was put into it.
And I just want to appreciate that
the next blog post in the underrated
category, we have the T zero HTTP request
smuggling, which This type of request
magning was thought to be impossible
because it doesn't really make sense
because if you're familiar with, um, with
request smuggling, you have basically
two headers to describe the length
of the body of the request, which is
content length and the transfer encoding.
Content length is the one we all know
because it's in almost every single
request with a body and transfer encoding.
Usually from one sent from
the client is not used, but is
the one that has the priority.
So request smuggling happens
with when this prior route.
prioritization is done incorrectly.
So usually you will have the transfer
and coding head and slightly modified
so that one component, let's say you're
reverse, you have reverse proxy in
the server or from your perspective,
first reverse proxy, then the server.
And it happens when one component does
not see the transfer and coding header.
So it chooses the content next header,
and the other component sees both.
So it prioritizes the transfer and
coding header, which was first ignored.
So this is the normal situation.
So the TL zero was thought to be
impossible because it works the
way that for, to the first, uh,
component to the reverse proxy.
You send the transfer and coding header
and you hope for it to be somehow
dropped by the second component.
Which normally shouldn't happen
because it's the one with the
priority, but It did work.
Um, I think what happened here,
if I were to guess, is that
first, it's an options request.
So maybe this code base was
not examined as thoroughly.
And then there's no content
length in this request at all.
So my guess would be that there was some
code that said, if there is no content
length header, then there's Treat the
content length as zero so it would treat
the body as zero even though there was
transfer encoding header and That's how
the smuggling happened and this happened
in the Google Um, Google cloud proxy.
That's the one that you always
see when you have the via 1.
1 Google request.
So the impact of it was huge because
you would basically send the request
like this and the second one down
here, it would be added to the queue.
So a random user would be redirected
to your collaborator server.
With your cookies as well.
So it's basically an account takeover
of random people and it worked on any
server using the Google reverse proxy.
So the impact of it is incredibly high.
And the reason I put it in
the underrated category.
It's also not because I think is what
it was mishandled because I think the
bounty for it was eight and a half K,
which I'm assuming is the maximum for
this, for this particular asset in the
Google VRP program, I just think compared
to the overall impact, this is very low.
Maybe it is not written in the blog post.
Maybe the hunters did scale it up
to multiple bug bounty programs
and maybe they didn't make it.
Tens or hundreds of thousands of
dollars, but it is not in this blog
post, so I'm assuming they didn't.
Um, and I would say this is underrated.
So this is the second honorable
mention in the underrated category.
And before we do the actual reward
for the most underrated report.
We'll jump to the next category
because the report that I chose
as the most underrated one is
also the third report overall.
And there could only be one candidate
for the most underrated report.
And it is what happened with Zendesk.
If you're not familiar, what happened
there is that Zendesk is the company
that's used to handle support tickets.
You can access it through the website,
but the way you know, we as users mostly
use it, I'm sure most of you have used
it at some point, maybe not knowing it.
Zendesk is you can reply to a
ticket by replying to the email.
And the way it works is that if
you reply to the email from the
same email, you created the ticket.
The whole ticket is also sent, sent to
all the people that are CCD in the ticket.
So they are added to the ticket.
and you can add people to the ticket
by adding them to the email as well.
So up until now, it's, it's all fine.
But the problem was Zendesk was not
verifying this email in any way.
So you could claim my email, send the,
the sort of reply to one of my, my
tickets in any company using Zendesk.
Then you would also CC to this
email your own email address and
The whole conversation would be
sent to your cc email address.
The reason the sort of root cause of
this is this lack of verifying the email.
Cause the, for this attack, you have
to send the email as me basically.
And obviously you don't have the,
the domain that allows you to do it.
So this is the lack of the verification
and Let's first focus on why I think this
is one of the top reports overall, and
let's then focus on why I think it is the
underrated one, because up until now, the
impact you have is you can basically read
any uh, Any ticket and a support ticket.
Of course, you also need to send.
When you send this email, you
need to know the idea of the
ticket, but they are numeric.
They're like 1234.
So this is not an issue.
But then the researcher also changed
it with the sort of way slack
allows users to sign up for slack.
You will also often have companies
that allow anyone with the email
address in the company domain
to access their slack instance.
And you could change this to claim
the support at company dot com
email by abusing login with Apple.
So it's a this is a really,
really severe impact as you can
access all the support tickets.
And you can also access the slack
in a specific configuration.
And I like this attack because verifying
the incoming email, that's what the email
DNS records like DMARC, SPF and other are
used, which is something I never focus on.
I don't even know which of
these email records means what.
And normally it doesn't have We don't
think about it as having a lot of impact.
But in this particular scenario, when
the system is receiving emails, it
is impactful, because we all know
this, that these records from being
out of scope of an hacker one page.
But it's out of scope when somebody
reports that a specific domain
does not have these DNS records.
But this is not the case here.
Here is the case where the code
of Zendesk that receives emails
It doesn't check for, for these
records on the domain of the sender.
So you can send, send the email
using the linux sendmail command and
it will, it will show as trusted.
And I just like when things we
all are aware of and we're all
kind of ignoring when things like
that all of a sudden create such
a huge impact like this company.
But now we'll jump to why
I think it is  underrated.
It is underrated because the response
by hacker one was that this is out of
scope because as I've said, these email
records, these email DNS records are
always out of scope and the triage didn't
realize these situations are different.
And he just closed this informative,
actually not out of scope, and I
wouldn't put a huge blame on them.
We know three years are overworked
and a mistake like this can happen.
But the worst thing is that also the
hacker and mediation did not help in
this case, which I think is a way bigger
problem because It was an attack with with
a lot of impact, and I think mediation
should help with this, but it didn't.
So the hunter would get probably
5, 000 from Zendesk, which
they kind of missed out on.
But then what they did is they
started looking for companies that are
basically using Zendesk, which is a lot.
A lot of companies use Zendesk,
and he started reporting this
attack there, and he made a total.
of over 50, 000.
So he actually 10 X his bounty for
this report due to the hacker one and
Zendesk closing it as informative,
which I think is a, it's a funny story.
And I'm, I feel.
A sense of satisfaction because
of it, because his report, which
was a, a good one, a good bag, his
report was mishandled, and then
neither Zendesk nor Hap hacker
one publicly apologized to them.
Even worse, Zendesk issued a public,
he, they condemned his actions publicly.
So yeah, I'm just really, really happy
for him to get the, the 50 K for it.
And in my opinion, this is
the third best report of 2024.
and it's the winner of the BB
re 2024 top underrated report.
Um, and uh, yeah, I hope that some
companies and maybe hacker one will take
away something from, from this story.
So this situation does not, these
situations do not happen in the future.
Then we jump to the second.
best report of 2024.
It's actually one bug that was reported
both to GitHub and GitLab, and this
is the SAML authentication bypass.
And it is another story of something
that probably, if I were the one auditing
this code, I would skip it because the
way SAML works, SAML is the XML format
that contains some signatures inside it.
And because the signatures are inside it,
you cannot just take the whole string.
generate, uh, a signature from it and then
verify it because the signature is inside.
So it cannot work like that.
It means that before you generate the
signature, you have to parse the XML.
You have to extract the, the part that
you're interested in to, to sign it.
And we know from the past that this
complexity, these sort of parsing, um,
process it's where bugs can happen.
And it happens here as well.
The.
The way hunters were able to bypass this,
they just put two signatures or two, two
things that were signed inside of this
Samuel and only one of them was verified
while the other one was actually used.
It was because the, the first
one was taken and it was not,
not the one that was actually
meaningful and you could basically.
Login is another user you would have
sort of your own email to which you
could log in in the in this part that was
actually signed with the proper signature.
And then in the other part that was not
signed, you would have any victim's email.
So it would be a zero click account
takeover service like account takeover.
I am not aware of any name.
mitigating circumstances in these cases.
So this led to account takeover on GitLab.
The same on github as well We do not see
the bounties for these reports But I'm
assuming it's max for both github and
github because I don't see a reason of of
why not so yeah, I really really love this
this bug and Really really good job for
the researchers And with that, we'll now
go to the winner of, in my opinion, the
best overall bug bounty report of 2024.
And it is this one.
It is the, the blog post about four
bugs in the Microsoft healthcare chat
bot, which Some of them will will be
aware of this because I already created
the video about this, this right up.
It has everything.
The impact is huge because you access
medical records of other users.
The complexity is nice.
We have four bugs.
The first one was the past traversal
in the sort of secondary past traversal
in the microservice and in the way you
you work with the API on the back end.
Then we have the
the escape of the sandbox by it.
Bypassing the allow list, then we
have another escape of the sandbox by
abusing something that is inside the
allow list and then finally we have,
um, reading the memory which is also
outside of this sandbox and we also
have a huge bounty of 204 1, 000.
So in my opinion, this is the
best bug bounty writeup of 2024.
If you want to see this one in
details, it is, uh, the video
is on your screen right now.
You can watch it in a second.
Um, for now, that's all
for the 2024 BBR rewards.
Here are all the reports that,
that have won and that were
mentioned during this video.
I'm very open to hear
your comments, uh, which.
Which ones do you agree with?
Which ones do you disagree with?
Is there anything I completely missed
and I didn't even mention it, and
you think it, it should be there.
I will be very, very interesting
to read your comments down below.
For now, thank you so much
for watching and goodbye.